我叫李奥纳多
My name is Leonardo,
现在
and right now,
我和我的兄弟们正陷入麻烦
my brothers and I are in a mess of trouble.
我们背后是垃圾小巷尽头的墙
Our backs are up against the wall in some trash-strewn alley,
东边最强大的匪帮
cornered by the toughest street gang
把我们逼到绝路
on the East Side.
看看这些怪胎
Look at the freaks.
穿着可笑的服装
What's with the dweeby costumes?
现在又不是万圣节
This ain't Halloween.
你们完蛋了 怪胎
You're going down, freaks!
没错
Yeah!
没人敢招惹紫龙帮
Nobody messes with The Purple Dragons,
尤其是穿着龟服的蠢货
especially wearing stupid turtle costumes!
他错了
He's wrong.
我们根本没穿衣服
We're not wearing costumes.
少年变异忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
[片头曲]
神龟报数
Turtles, count it off!
一 二 三 四
One, Two, Three, Four
忍者神龟 变异链式反应
Turtles! Mutant chain reaction
忍者神龟 生存在地下
Turtles! Livin' underground
忍者神龟 修练忍术
Turtles! Ninjitsu action
忍者神龟 在这个了不起的城市
Turtles! It's a shell of a town
神龟报数
Turtles, count it off!
一、恪守武术之道
One! Live by the code of the martial arts
二、人不犯我 我不犯人
Two! Never fight unless someone else starts
三、无论如何 生死与共
Three! Always stick together no matter what
四、若别无他法 该出手时就出手
Four! If all else fails, then it's time to kick butt
我爱当一只...
I love bein' a -
我爱当一只神龟
I love bein' a turtle
少年变异忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
神龟报数
Turtles, count it off!
一 二 三 四
One, Two, Three, Four
忍者神龟 无人能及
Turtles! There's no one better
忍者神龟 小心施莱德
Turtles! Watch out for Shredder
忍者神龟 他们独一无二
Turtles! They're like no others
忍者神龟 那些少年兄弟
Turtles! Those teenage brothers
一 二 三 四
One, Two, Three, Four
少年变异忍者神龟
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
风云突变
记住 想成为真正的忍者
Remember, to be a true ninja,
你们必须与影子融为一体
you must become one with the shadows.
黑暗赋予忍者力量
Darkness gives the ninja power,
而光明会暴露忍者的行踪
while light reveals the ninja's presence.
现在
Now
你们能否熄灭这火焰
can you extinguish this flame
而不暴露自己?
without revealing yourselves?
声音太大 多纳泰罗
Too noisy, Donatello.
太笨拙了 米开朗基罗
Too clumsy, Michelangelo.
糟糕的选择 拉斐尔
Poor choice, Raphael.
干得好 李奥纳多
Well done, Leonardo.
老师的宠儿
Teacher's pet.
辍学的忍者
Ninja drop-out.
哦哟
Ooh!
孩子们
My sons.
啊 我的孩子们
Ah, My sons.
要成为真正的忍者
If you are to become true ninja,
你们必须更加努力
you must work harder.
你们的人生道路不会轻松
Your path in life will not be an easy one.
外面的世界对你们并不友好
The outside world will not be a friendly place for you.
你们四个如此与众不同
You four are different in ways
地上的人们不会理解的
the surface dwellers would never understand.
为了生存
To survive,
你们必须掌握我教的这些技巧
you must master these skills I teach you,
忍术中的潜行与隐遁之术
ninjitsu powers of stealth and secrecy.
你们必须成为影丸 即影子武士
You must become kage, shadow warriors,
绝不能被外界所察觉
and you must never be discovered by the outside world.
嗯? 那是什么声音
Eh? What is that noise?
哇! 地震了
Whoa! Earthquake!
在纽约?
In New York?
可能吧 但几率不大
Possible, but not likely.
那些是什么东西
What are those things?
纽约的蟑螂吗
New York City cockroaches?
不管是什么东西
Whatever they are,
它们来错地方了
they picked the wrong party to crash!
嘿 李奥
Hey, Leo,
快速出击
think fast!
我们得帮帮斯普林特老师
We have to help Master Splinter!
快来
Come on!
小心
Look out!
哦 不
Oh, no!
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter!
不
No!
这些到底是什么鬼东西
What the shell are those things?
不管它们是什么
Whatever they were--
现在都成废铜烂铁了
they're junk now.
大伙儿
Guys,
斯普林特
Splinter.
我们必须找到斯普林特
We've got to find Splinter.
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter,
你能听见吗
can you hear me?
多纳泰罗
Donatello,
你有没有办法...
Donatello, any way to--
你在干什么
What are you doing?
龟壳电话
Shell cell.
我在呼叫斯普林特老师
I'm calling Master Splinter
希望能行
I hope.
我该按哪个键才能接听
which button do you press to answer this thing?
喂?
Hello?
斯普林特老师 你还好吧
Master Splinter, are you all right?
有人吗
Hello?
斯普林特老师...
Master Splinter...
破设备
Stupid device.
你不用按任何按钮
you don't have to press any buttons.
已经接通了
You already answered it.
啊 李奥纳多
Ah. Leonardo,
不管那些机器是什么
whatever those mechanical menaces are,
它们已经啃穿了我们房子的支柱
they have managed to eat through the support structure of our home.
我们必须马上离开
We must leave right away.
在南端的老下水道枢纽处汇合
Meet me at the old drainage junction near South Point.
如果我们走南边的管道
If we take the south conduit,
它与旧的下水道有个交点
it'll intersect with the old drainage tunnel.
我们在那里与你会合 老师
We'll meet you there, Sensei.
他说什么 他说什么了
What'd he say? What'd he say?
提到我了吗
Did he mention me?
再见 开裂的水管
Good-bye, broken pipe.
再见 脏兮兮的付费电话
Good-bye, grungy pay phone.
再见 凹陷的井盖
Good-bye, dented manhole cover.
再见了 我甜蜜的家
Good-bye, home, sweet home.
我来了 残酷的世界
Hello, cruel world.
走吧
Come on.
看来那些东西来过这儿了
Looks like those things have been through here.
这些墙已经严重受损
These walls are seriously compromised.
幸好屋顶还没塌下来
It's lucky this roof hasn't caved in.
你刚说什么
You were saying?
没法前进 也没法后退
Can't go forward. Can't go back.
看来只能往上走了
Looks like we go up.
去地面可不是好主意
Hitting the surface is a bad idea.
我们别无选择了 李奥
We've got no other way to go, Leo.
好吧
All right,
但是我们到下一个井盖就下去
but we're only going up to go down the next manhole.
明白吗? 不准乱逛
Got it? No fooling around.
记住老师说的话
Remember what Sensei said.
被人看到会很危险
It's dangerous for us to be seen,
更别说被抓住了
let alone captured.
我们需要保持隐蔽
We need to stay out of sight.
这话我们听了一千遍了 李奥
We got it the first thousand times, Leo.
跟着我走就是了
Just follow my lead.
李奥 快上去
Come on, Leo. Move it.
我可不想一直盯着你的屁股看
I don't want to be staring at your butt any longer than I have to.
嘘 各位
Shh. Guys!
啊 发现井盖
Ah, manhole cover,
十二点钟方向
12 o'clock.
又怎么了
Now what?
好极了 真是好极了
Great. Just great.
乌龟运气从不让人失望
The old turtle luck working true to form.
隐蔽得真好 拉夫
Way to be stealthy, Raph.
是的 新泽西都能听见这动静了
Yeah. I don't think they heard you over in "Joisey."
搭把手
Give me a hand.
想都别想 米奇
Don't even think about it, Mikey.
哎 懒得理你们
Ah, forget you guys.
我来自己推
I'll push it myself.
老兄 真是大丰收
Oh, man, what a score.
快躲起来 拉夫
Hide, Raph.
快点 赶紧
Come on. Hurry.
不好
No.
糟糕的选择 拉斐尔
Poor choice, Raphael.
你们看到那家伙的怂样了吗
Did you see the way that guy squirmed
我们抢他钱的时候
when we took his cash?
像小绵羊一样
Sheep, man,
注定被我们这群狼薅光
sheep to be fleeced by us wolves.
哦 天哪
Oh, man.
想象一下待会儿
Imagine their surprise
他们打开车门的时候会有多惊讶
when they open the back of that truck.
这正是斯普林特老师所说的情况
This is exactly what Master Splinter was talking about.
我们必须把他救出来
We've got to get him out of there.
最后一个到屋顶的是笨蛋
Last one to the roof hatched from a rotten egg!
我们可以在第三和第一大道截住他们
We can cut them off at Third and First.
如果我们疯狂地跑的话
If we run like crazy.
难道有别的跑法吗
Is there any other way to run?
哈哈! 没错
Ha ha! Yeah!
你们太慢了
You guys are too slow!
嘿
Hey!
哇! 哇! 哇
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
嗯 春天的清香味
Mm, springtime fresh.
喔吼
Whoo-hoo!
啊 老下水道枢纽
Ah, the old drainage junction.
我的孩子们在哪里
Now where are my sons?
【过场动画】
嘿 二吨 看着卡车
Hey, Two Ton, watch the truck.
我们可不希望有人来
We wouldn't want somebody to
偷我们偷来的钱
steal our stolen money.
哈哈
Ha ha.
嘿 这里禁止停车
Hey, this is a no-parking zone.
这是你的罚单
Here's your ticket,
这是你的罚款
and here's your fine.
干得漂亮 米奇
Nice work, Mikey.
咳 都是忍者该做的
Eh, it's a ninja thing.
现在 咱们把拉斐救出来
Now let's get Raph out of there.
哎 没人用经典的老式挂锁了吗
Man, whatever happened to good old-fashioned padlocks?
嘿 那还有什么意思呢
Heh. Where's the fun in that?
这个交给我了
This one's all mine.
你说什么 拉斐尔
What's that, Raphael?
你得大声点 老兄
You're gonna have to speak up, dude.
我听不见
I can't hear you.
好的 这我听到了
Okay, I heard that.
我正试着工作呢
I'm trying to work here.
嘿 拉夫
Hey, Raph.
欢迎回来 兄弟
Welcome back, bro!
真是个暴脾气
What a hothead.
嗷! 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷!
Ow! Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow! Ow!
呃 拉夫
Uh, Raph?
没时间胡闹了
We don't have time for this.
为什么呢
And why not?
因为我们这里不止有我们
Because we're not alone.
看看这些怪胎
Look at the freaks.
穿的什么蠢服装
What's with the dweeby costumes?
现在又不是万圣节
This ain't Halloween.
你们完蛋了 怪胎
You're going down, freaks!
没人敢招惹紫龙帮
Nobody messes with The Purple Dragons,
尤其是穿着龟服的蠢货
especially wearing stupid turtle costumes!
咱们快离开这里
Let's get outta here!
我跟你一起
I'm with you!
快走 快走 快走
Go, go, go!
给我点绿色
Gimme some green!
嗯 这比预想的要简单
Well, that was easier than expected.
希望这样的家伙再多来点
I hope there are more of those guys.
我才刚热完身呢
I'm just getting warmed up.
呃 好吧
Uh, well,
看来你如愿以偿了 拉斐小子
looks like you got your wish, Raphie boy.
那些家伙是忍者吗
Are those guys ninjas?
嗯 他们确实有忍者风范
Well, they're certainly ninja-esque.
做好应对一切的准备
Be ready for anything.
我肯定会很享受这个的
I am so gonna enjoy this.
不错的龙踢腿
Nice dragon kick.
啊 漂亮的凤凰拳
Ah, sweet double phoenix punch.
嘿 知道这招吗
Hey, you know this one?
多尼 是我们在打他们
Don, are we beating them,
还是他们在打我们
or are they beating us?
等我们赢了再问我 米奇
Ask me again when we're winning, Mikey.
是的 我也是这么想的
Yeah, that's what I thought.
我们得揍扁多少个蠢货
How many of these goons do we have to bap
他们才会长教训
before they get the hint?
是吗 他们一直不停地冒出来
Really. They just keep coming.
是时候启动B计划了
Time to switch to plan B.
多纳泰罗
Donatello?
马上就好 李奥
Almost there, Leo.
巴士即将离开这里
This bus now leaving for
前往任何别的地方
anywhere but here!
快点! 我们出发
Come on! We're going!
哦! 开得真好 多尼
Whoa! Nice driving, Don,
对于一只没驾照的乌龟来说
for a turtle with no license!
嘿 你是想要美观
Hey, you want pretty,
还是想要实用
or you want effective?
我得告诉你 今天真是诡异到极点了
I gotta tell you, this has been one mondo bizarro day.
首先是地下那些金属机器人
First, all those metal robot things underground.
还有那些忍者是怎么回事
And what's with all those ninjas?
纽约市的忍者
Ninjas in New York City?
除了我们
Besides us?
这太不对劲了
It's just not right.
说到不对劲
Talk about not right.
快来看看这个
Check this out.
让我看看钱 宝贝
Show me the money, baby!
喔吼
Whoo-hoo!
这可不是谁捡到就归谁 米奇
This isn't finders keepers, Mikey.
伙计们 看好这些钱 行吗
Take care of this money, will you, guys?
你看见了吗
Did you see that?
几个开装甲车的小绿人
Some little green men in an armored car
朝我们扔了一大堆钱
just threw a bunch of money at us!
呵呵 新手
Rookie.
嘿
Hey!
师父 你没事
Sensei, you're all right!
斯普林特! 好啊
- Splinter! - Yeah!
是的 我也很高兴看到你们
Yes, well, I'm glad to see you, too,
我的孩子们
my sons.
斯普林特老师
Master Splinter,
今天发生了太多事
so much has happened today.
好的 好的
Yes, yes.
稍后有的是时间告诉我
There will be time to tell me all about it later
李奥纳多
Leonardo,
但首先
but first,
我想先带你们回家
I wish to take you all home.
家
Home?
我们没有家了
We got no home.
那些机器人把我们的家毁了
Those robots trashed our pad.
还记得吗 师父
Remember, Sensei?
别担心
Do not worry.
我想我已经找到了方法
I think I have found a solution
解决我们当前住房问题
to our current housing problem.
跟我来 孩子们
Follow me, my sons.
卡哇邦....
Cowabun--
啊
Aah!
这不好笑 拉夫
Not funny, Raph!
哦 当然好笑
Oh, yes, it is.
超赞的滑行
Wicked slide!
无意冒犯 斯普林特老师
No offense, Master Splinter,
但这地方看起来不怎么样
but this place doesn't seem so great.
用心去看 米开朗基罗
Look with your heart, Michelangelo,
而不是用你的眼睛
and not your eyes.
嗯 好吧
Um, okay.
往这边走
And walk this way.
哇
Wow!
这简直太棒了
This is beyond awesome!
我可以把这里改造一下
I could really tune this space up.
这间屋子 归我了
This room here, mine.
你站的那里 也是我的
And where you're standing, also mine.
听着孩子们 改变是好事
You see, my sons, change is good.
我们完全赞同 斯普林特老师
We couldn't agree more, Master Splinter.
很好
Good.
这次换你们几个来打扫吧
So let's see you boys clean up for a change.
这房间太脏了
This chamber is filthy.
唉 老兄
Aw, man.
先生 我...我...
Sir? I--I--
我的手下们
my men,
我们...我们把运钞的装甲车弄丢了
we--we lost the armored car with the money.
但是我们是被袭击了
But we were attacked
被某种空手道青蛙生物之类的袭击
by some sort of karate frog creatures or something.
他们打了我们一个措手不及
They took us by surprise.
那不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
够了
Enough.
我保证 先生 我不会再让你失望了
I promise, sir, I won't fail you again.
我知道
I know.
你不会再让我失望了 永远
You won't fail me again, ever.
不 先生 求你了
No, sir! Please!
【片尾】